As a university student, I’ve come to realise just how little I know about money.
身为大学生，我渐渐意识到，自己对钱的了解竟是如此之少。
I’ve come to the brutal realisation that Australia’s youth are being done a great disservice by not receiving any consistent financial education.
我认识到一个残酷的现实：澳大利亚的年轻人因为得不到任何持续的理财教育，正深受其害。
Diving headfirst into the crash course of starting university, I’ve quickly tried to get myself up to speed with the financial terms of the modern era to help manage my personal finances.
刚上大学就像一头扎进了一门速成课，我赶紧设法让自己熟悉当今时代的金融术语，好帮自己打理个人财务。
I’ve read some financial education books, done some online learning, and spoken to my nearest and dearest for their pearls of financial wisdom.
我读过一些理财教育方面的书，在网上学过一些课程，还向至亲好友讨教过他们在理财方面的金玉良言。
There are undoubtedly hundreds of great resources out there for those wishing to improve their financial literacy, but while I was researching, I still kept wishing that I didn’t have to play catch-up with the money world.
毫无疑问，对想提升理财素养的人来说，现有的优质资源数以百计；但我在查资料时，还是一直希望自己不必去追赶金钱世界的步伐。
I felt that I was sailing the financial seas with no skills and no life jacket!
我感觉自己正航行在金融的大海上，既毫无技能，又没有救生衣！
However, after talking to my friends who felt the same, I quickly realised that it wasn’t my ignorance but the lack of financial education in our schooling system that is leaving high schoolers seriously behind in the modern world of money.
然而，在和有同感的朋友们聊过之后，我很快意识到，不是我无知，而是我们的学校教育体系缺少理财教育，才让高中生在现代金钱世界里严重落后。
Let’s compare a theoretical financial education subject to the standard compulsory English class.
我们来把一门设想中的理财教育科目与常规的英语必修课比较一下。
On average, English may not be the most popular subject, but it’s consistently on the schedule throughout high school, with all students graduating fluent in English.
总体来说，英语也许不是最受欢迎的科目，但在整个高中阶段，它始终都在课表上，所有学生毕业时英语都很流利。
A financial education subject should do just the same.
理财教育科目也应该同样如此。
It shouldn’t be just a one-day event but a course integrated throughout the whole of high school that would allow students to gradually expand their financial literacy, and would prevent the need for a ‘catch-up’ phase once we’re out on our own after graduation.
它不应只是为期一天的活动，而应是一门融入整个高中阶段的课程，让学生逐步拓展理财素养，也免得我们毕业后独立生活时还需要经历一个“追赶”阶段。
In the same way that learning a language or new skills takes time, building financial skills requires practice and years to gradually accumulate bits and pieces of knowledge.
正如学习一门语言或新技能需要时间一样，培养理财技能也需要练习，需要用多年时间逐步积累点点滴滴的知识。
Giving young people the opportunity to become familiar with the world of money would provide them with a great advantage to enter adulthood with confidence and security so that they are able to manage their own money and look after themselves.
让年轻人有机会熟悉金钱世界，会给他们带来很大的优势，使他们可以带着自信和安全感步入成年，从而能够管理自己的钱财、照顾好自己。